Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Reel Tapes, 1954-12-14 to 1972-11-21
  - Box 24, 1961 -- 1964; 19 10 1/2" open reel tapes
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, strings, no. 2, op. 87, C major, 1963 December 11; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 8)
      1st mvt: PR-A5-4564 T-7 –- 2nd mvt: PR-A5-4565 T-1 –- 3rd mvt: PR-A5-4566 T-4-revised 12/16 -– 4th mvt: PR-A5-4567 T-3
      15 ips Ampex
    - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Trios, piano, strings, op. 65, F minor, 1963 December 11; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 9)
      1st mvt: PR-A5-5883-T-9 –- 2nd mvt: PR-A5-5884-T-5-revised 12/16 -– 3rd mvt: PR-A5-5885 T-1-revised 12/16 –- 4th mvt: PR-A5-5886-T-3
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Trios, piano, strings, op. 70. No. 2, 1963 December 11; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 10)
      Master Transfer
      PR-A3-4529 - 1st Mvt. T-6-Revised 12/16 -- 4530 - 2nd Mvt. T-7 -- 4531 - 3rd Mvt. T-4 -- 4532 - 4th Mvt. T-9 [Total] Time 25:07
      12/11/63 DG - JFP
    - Arensky, Anton Stepanovich, 1861-1906. Trios, piano, strings, no. 1, op. 32, D minor, 1963 October 17; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 11)
      Information handwritten in black marker and red ink on box:
      1st Mvt. - PR-A5-4586-T-12 -- 2nd Mvt. - PR-A5-4587-T-8 Revised 12/16 -- 3rd Mvt. - PR-A5-4588-T-3 -- 4th Mvt. - PR-A5-4589-T-3 [Total] Time 25:05
      15 ips Ampex Monaural
      12/12/63 J.N; J.P.
    - Rózsa, Miklós, 1907-1995. Sinfonia concertante, violin, violoncello, orchestra, op. 29. Tema con variazioni -- Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741. Concertos, violin, violoncello, string orchestra, RV 547, B♭ major, 1963 October 7; 1963 October 10; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 12)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; unidentified orchestra
      Rozsa Tema Con Variazioni PR-A5-4536-T-3 11:14 Pauses shortened 12/16 -- Vivaldi Concerto for violin, cello, strings & cembalo PR-A5-4538-T-8 for I & II Mvts.; T-6 for III Mvt. 9:45
      12/12/1963 J.N.; J.P.
    - Turina, Joaquín, 1882-1949. Trios, piano, strings, no. 1, op. 35, 1963 November 6; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 13)
      1st Mvt. - PR-A5-5876-T-5 -- 2nd Mvt. - PR-A5-5877-T-3 -- 3rd Mvt. - PR-A5-5878-T-5 Revised 12/16 [Total] Time 19:22
      12/12/63 J.N.; J.P.
    - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Divertimenti, H. XI. Selections; arr., 1963 December 12; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 14)
      Performed by Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; unidentified chamber orchestra
      Haydn Divertimento for cello and chamber orch. G. Piatigorsky PR-A5-4537-T-7 9:26
    - Halvorsen, Johan, 1864-1935. Passacaglia, violin, viola, G minor; arr. -- Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Suite italienne, violoncello, piano; arr., 1963 December 12; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 15)
      Halvorsen Passacaglia PR-A5-4540-T-3 5:57 -- Stravinsky Suite Italienne PR-A5-4539-T-4 15:28 Pause after Serenata longer by 2 sec.
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, violins, violas, violoncello, K. 515, C major, 1964 March 26; 1964 March 27; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 16)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; William Primrose, viola; Israel Baker, violin; Virginia Majewski, viola
      15” Mono
      Mozart Quintette K.-V. 515
      NBC - Studio A - March 26, 27, 1964
      1st Mvt. - 8:21 -- 2nd Mvt. - 7:20 -- 3rd Mvt. - 4:57 -- 4th Mvt. - 6:43
      Master Transfer 15 ips Ampex Comp.
      JFP - IF 4/8/1964
    - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Quintets, piano, strings, op. 81, A major, 1964 March 24; 1964 March 25; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 17)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Jacob Lateiner, piano; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; William Primrose, viola; Israel Baker, violin
      NBC - Studio A - 3/24, 25/64
      1st Mvt. - Take 12 -- 2nd Mvt. - Take 5 -- 3rd Mvt. - Take 7 -- 4th Mvt. - Take 3 and 5
      Not edited; No Master made
      [written in large letters:] Not Passed
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Trios, piano, strings, op. 1. No. 1, 1964 April 9; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 18)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Jacob Lateiner, piano
      1st Mvt. - 6:59 -- 2nd Mvt. - 6:31 -- 3rd Mvt. - 4:52 -- 4th Mvt. - 7:10
      Master Transfer 15 ips - Ampex - Monaural
      J.F.P. - I.F. 4/9/64
    - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Quintets, piano, strings, op. 81, A major, 1964 November 9; 1964 November 10; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 24, Reel 19)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Jacob Lateiner, piano; Israel Baker, violin; Joseph De Pasquale, viola
      Heifetz-Piatigorsky Concerts
      RCA Studio “A” - Nov. 9, 10, 1964
      1st Mvt.: RR-A3-4883 Take 7 8:51 -- 2nd Mvt.: RR-A3-4884 Take 4 9:42 -- 3rd Mvt.: RR-A3-4885 Take 3 3:29 -- 4th Mvt.: RR-A3-4886 Take 3 6:26 [Total time:] 28:28 [?]
      15 ips - Monaural Ampex Comp. NAB
      +6 1 KC & 12 KC
      J.N. - J.F.P. 11/17/1964
  - Box 25, 1953 -- 1972; 17 10 1/2" open reel tapes
    Thomas, Milton; Steuber, Lillian; Piatigorsky, Gregor; Rosenthal, Paul; Baker, Israel; Harshman, Allan; Smith, Brooks; De Pasquale, Joseph; Amoyal, Pierre; Lateiner, Jacob; Lesser, Laurence; Schonbach, Sanford
    - Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805. Sonatas, violin, violoncello, D major -- Françaix, Jean, 1912-1997. Trios, strings -- Glière, Reinhold Morit︠s︡evich, 1875-1956. Duets, violin, violoncello, op. 39. Preli︠u︡dii︠a︡ -- Martinů, Bohuslav, 1890-1959. Duets, violin, violoncello [unspecified], 1964 November 18; 1964 November 11; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 1)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Joseph De Pasquale, viola
      [Side #1] Heifetz - Piatigorsky concerts with Joseph De Pasquale
      Recording Hollywood Studio A-RCA
      Boccherini Sonata for Violin & Cello (Recorded 11/18/64) RR-A3-4888 T-5 8:16
      Francaix Trio for Violin, Viola & Cello (Recorded 11/11/64) RR-A3-4887 1st Mvt.- T-5 -- 2nd Mvt.- T-7 -- 3rd Mvt.- T-10 -- 4th Mvt.- T-10 (Announcement Opening of 3rd Mvt.) Total Time 9:57
      [Side #2] Gliere Prelude, OP. 39 for Violin & Cello (Recorded 11/18/64) RR-A3-4890 T-3 2:16
      Martinu Duo for Violin & Cello (Recorded 11/18/64) RR-A3-4889 T-9 6:58 (Including Pause)
      15 IPS - NAB - Monaural Master Transfer
      (Frequency Run at Head End) RB JFP 12/1/64
    - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Preludes, piano (1926); arr. -- Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. Selections; arr., 1965 April 13; 1965 April 28; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 2)
      Mono [Reel] 1; 4-28-65; 15”/sec
      Gershwin Album: J. Heifetz - B. Smith RCA Studio “A” - 4/13/65
      1. Preludes - SR-A3-1478 I - Take 4 1:28; II - Take 6 2:37; III - Take 6 1:10 -- 2. Summertime & A Woman is a Sometime Thing - SR-A3-1473 Take 1 3:17 -- 3. My Man’s Gone Now - SR-A3-1474 Take 2 3:42 -- 4. It Ain’t Necessarily So - SR-A3-1475 Take 2 2:20 -- 5. Bess, You Is My Woman Now - SR-A3-1477 Take 4 2:48 -- 6. Tempo Di Blues - SR-A3-1476 Take 3 2:43
      Monaural - Master Transfer - 15 ips -Ampex
      IF - JFP 4/28/65 LP Serial No. SR-RM-1481
    - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Selections -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Valses nobles et sentimentales. No 6-7 -- Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963. Mouvements perpétuels -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Carnaval des animaux. Cygne -- Ibert, Jacques, 1890-1962. Histoires. Petit âne blanc, 1965 April 14; 1965 April 29; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 3)
      Mono [Reel] 2; 4-28-65; 15”
      French Album (To Couple with Gershwin Album): J. Heifetz, B. Smith Recorded RCA Studio “A” - 4/14/65
      1. La Chevelure SR-A3-3853 T-3 2:30 -- 2. Golliwogg’s Cakewalk 3854 T-6 2:24 -- 3. Beau Soir 3852 T-3 2:00 -- 4. Valses Nobles et Sentimentales 3848 T-2 3:16 -- 5. Movements Perpetuels 3849 T-1 3:41 -- 6. The Swan 3851 T-6 2:15 -- 7. Little White Donkey 3850 T-3 1:36
      Mono Master Transfer
      LP - SR-RM-148L IF-JFP 4/29/65
    - Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964. Divertimenti, op. 37. No. 2, 1965 April 16; 1965 May 1; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 4)
      5/1/65 15ips
      Toch: Divertimento, Op. 37, No. 2 for Violin and Cello J. Heifetz, G. Piatigorsky
      Recorded RCA Studio “A” - 4/16/65
      SR-A3-1480
      I - Flott und Lustig Take 8 1:50; :09 Pause -- II - Adagio Take 12 3:24; :08 Pause -- III - Vivace Molto Take 9 1:33 [Total time:] 7:04
      Monaural Master Transfer Ampex - 5/1/65 IF - JFP
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Quartets, piano, strings, no. 3, op. 60, C minor, 1965 August 17; 1965 August 18; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 5)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Sanford Schonbach, viola; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Jacob Lateiner, piano
      Information handwritten in red and blue ink on box:
      Mono - NAB - 15 ips
      Brahms Quartette in C Minor for Piano, Violin, Viola & Cello; J. Lateiner, J. Heifetz, S. Schonbach, G. Piatigorsky; Recorded Hollywood Studio “A” - 8/17-18/1965
      1st Mvt - SRA3-5868 Take 8 8:55 -- 2nd Mvt - SRA3-5869 Take 9 3:48 [line drawn underneath the latter time] split -- 3rd Mvt - SRA3-5870 Take 5 8:05 -- 4th Mvt - SRA3-5871 Take 2 8:58; [Total time:] 29:46
      Ampex 15 ips - Master Transfer
      1KC and 12 KC at beginning, at +6 for level
      IF-JFP 9/2/65
    - Khachaturi︠a︡n, Aram Ilʹich, 1903-1978. Sonatas, violin, piano, 1966 February 8; 1966 February 10; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 6)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Lillian Steuber, piano
      K. Khachaturian - Sonata, Op. 1; J. Heifetz - L. Steuber; Hollywood Studio A - Feb. 8, 1966
      First mvt.: TR-A3-2186 Take 3 5:57 -- Second mvt.: TR-A3-2187 Take 4 4:05 -- Third mvt.: TR-A3-2188 Take 4 5:14 [Total time:] 15:16
      Master Transfer Ampex - 15 IPS - Monaural 2/10/66 I.F., J.P
    - Ferguson, Howard, 1908-1999. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 1, op. 2, 1966 February 7; 1966 February 10; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 7)
      Ferguson Sonata No. 1; J. Heifetz - L. Steuber; Hollywood Studio A - Feb. 7, 1966
      First mvt.: TR-A3-2183 Take 5 4:14 -- Second mvt.: TR-A3-2183 [4?] Take 6 2:17 -- Third mvt.: TR-A3-2185 Take 2 7:15 [Total time:] 13:46
    - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 1, op. 75, D minor, 1967 May 3; 1967 May 8; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 8)
      Side 1. Saint-Saens Sonata No. 1 in D; J. Heifetz - B. Smith
      I. 1st Mvt./2nd Mvt. - UR-A3-1519-T-4 12:10 -- II. 3rd Mvt./4th Mvt. - UR-A3-1520-T-3 9:10 [Total time:] 21:20
      Master Transfer 15 ips - Ampex - Mono Full Track Recorded 5/3/67
      Hwd. Studio A; J.N. - JFP 5/8/67
    - Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Belsazars gästabud. Suite. Nocturne; arr. -- Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Capriccio-valse -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Stikhotvorenii︠a︡. Margaritki -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Oriental sketch -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Nana; arr. -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Jota; arr., 1967 May 2 -- 1967 May 4; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 9)
      Side 2 - Miscellaneous Group - J. Heifetz - B. Smith
      1. Sibelius - Nocturne - UR-A3-1523-T-4 3:04 -- 2. Wieniawski - Capriccio-Valse 1525-T-1 3:38 -- 3. Rachmaninoff - Daisies 1526-T-5 1:45 -- 4. Rachmaninoff - Oriental Sketch 1528-T-2 1:28 -- 5. Falla - Nana 1527-T-1 2:08 -- 6. Falla - Jota 1522-T-2 2:46
      Master Transfer 15 IPS - Ampex - Mono Full Track Recorded 5/2, 3, 4/67
      Hwd. “A” J.N. - JFP 5/8/67
    - Spohr, Louis, 1784-1859. Doppelquartett, no. 1, 1968 June 24; 1968 June 25; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 10)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Israel Baker, violin; Milton Thomas, viola; Pierre Amoyal, violin; Paul Rosenthal, violin; Allan Harshman, viola; Laurence Lesser, violoncello
      Heifetz - Piatigorsky Concerts
      Spohr: Double Quartette, Op. 65, with I. Baker, M. Thomas, P. Amoyal, P. Rosenthal, A. Harshman, L. Lesser
      First Mvt. - WR-A3-1504 Master Take 7 9:04 -- Second Mvt. - WR-A3-1505 Master Take 5 4:13 -- Third Mvt. - WR-A3-1506 Master Take 3 2:55 -- Fourth Mvt. - WR-A3-1507 Master Take 8 6:03
      Recorded June 24, 25, 1968 - Scottish Rite Aud. L.A.
      Monaural 15 ips - Ampex Master Dub
      Hollywood TM-1 7/24/68 AZ. - J.F.P.
    - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Trios, piano, strings, op. 90, E minor, 1968 July 1; 1968 July 2; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 11)
      Information handwritten in red and black ink on box:
      Dvorak: Piano Trio (in E Minor) Op. 90 “Dumky” with Jacob Lateiner
      First Mvt./Second Mvt. - WR-A3-1493 Master Take 6 4:04/5:32 -- Third Mvt. - WR-A3-1494 Master Take 8 5:20 -- Fourth Mvt. - WR-A3-1495 Master Take 1 3:52 -- Fifth Mvt. - WR-A3-1496 Master Take 1 3:26 -- Sixth Mvt. - WR-A3-1497 Master Take 3 4:12
      Recorded July 1, 2, 1968 - Scottish Rite Aud. L.A.
      15 ips - Monaural - Ampex - Master Dub
      [in red ink:] NOTE: New Cello Cadenza in 2nd Mvt. Inserted 9/27/68 Low level - will be raised in master
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Quintets, violins, violas, violoncello, op. 111, G major, 1968 September 16; 1968 September 17; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 12)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Israel Baker, violin; Milton Thomas, viola; Paul Rosenthal, violin
      Brahms: Quintette No. 2 in G, Op. 111, with I. Baker, M. Thomas, P. Rosenthal
      First Mvt. - WR-A3-6717 - Take 13 Master - 9:34 -- Second Mvt. - WR-A3-6718 - Take 3 Master - 5:34 -- Third Mvt. - WR-A3-6719 - Take 6 Master - 4:27 -- Fourth Mvt. - WR-A3-6720 - Take 12 Master - 4:02 [Total time:] 23:37
      Recorded September 16, 17, 1968 - Scottish Rite Auditorium
      Master Transfer; Monaural - Ampex Comp. NAB 15 IPS Full Track
      Take 8 of Fourth Mvt. on end (For Laughs!)
      Hollywood TM-1 9/26/68 AZ. - J.F.P.
    - Heifetz Recital Part 1: Franck, César, 1822-1890. Sonatas, violin, piano, A major, 1972 October 23; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 13)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [Brooks Smith, piano]
      Information handwritten in black and blue ink on box:
      Heifetz Recital; Pavillion of Music Center; Los Angeles; October 23, 1972
      Franck Sonata in A Major
      Applause - Tuning :50 -- First Mvt. 5:03 -- :05 -- Second Mvt. 7:19 -- :00 [originally written as :05 and crossed out?] -- Third Mvt. 6:31 -- :06 -- Fourth Mvt. 5:29 -- Applause :25 [Total time:] 25:58
      15 ips Mono Transfer
      Studio B Hollywood 11/21/72 AZ-JFP O.K.
    - Heifetz Recital Part 2: Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Sonatas, violin, piano, op. 18, E♭ major, 1972 October 23; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 14)
      Strauss Sonata in E-Flat Major
      First Mvt. 9:59 -- Tuning :16 -- Second Mvt. 7:19 -- :06 -- Third Mvt. 7:27 -- Applause :25 [Total time:] 25:30 [?]
    - Heifetz Recital Part 3: Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 3. Selections -- Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959. Baal Shem. Nigun -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Plus que lente; arr., 1972 October 23; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 15)
      Heifetz Recital; Pavillion of Music Center; October 23, 1972
      Bach: Partita in E: Prelude 3:12 Take 2 from Studio -- :08 -- Loure 3:05 -- :03 -- Gigue 1:40 -- Applause :16 -- :10 -- Bloch: Negun 5:05 -- :08 -- Debussy: La Plus Que Lente 3:59 [Total time:] 17:39
    - Heifetz Recital Part 4: Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Études-tableaux, op. 39. No 6; arr. -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Nana; arr. -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Chasse -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Tzigane -- Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Songs from Shakespeare’s plays. Arise; arr., 1972 October 23; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 16)
      Rachmaninoff: Etude-Tableau 1:39 Take 3 from Studio -- :10 -- Falla: Nana 2:05 -- :06 -- Kreisler: La Chasse 1:46 Take 3 from Studio -- :08 -- Ravel: Tzigane 7:54 -- Applause :10 -- Castelnuovo-Tedesco: Sea Murmurs 1:17 -- Applause :22 [Total time:] 16:08 [?] -- Speech (Not to be on record)
    - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Sonatas, violin, continuo, HWV 373, E major -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Sonatas, violin, continuo, HWV 371, D major -- Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Lark, 1953 November 30; 1954 March 30; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 25, Reel 17)
      Jascha Heifetz Ampex 15 ips
      11:35 1 - Handel - Sonata No. 6 (E3-RC-2517-2520)
      11:30 2 - Handel - Sonata No. 4 (E3-RC-2521-2524)
      9:20 3 - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, “The Lark” (E3-RC-2525)
      Information handwritten in blue pencil on sheet of notepaper in envelope inside box:
      In Sonata #6 (E Major) Handel In Adagio Cantabile - in 9th bar - 1/2 bar missing (erased by accident) -- by me - J.H.
  - Box 26, 1953 -- 1961; 17 10 1/2" open reel tapes
    Petri, Egon; Pennario, Leonard; Piatigorsky, Gregor; Chicago Symphony Orchestra; Reiner, Fritz; Cantelli, Guido; New York Philharmonic; Bussotti, Carlo
    - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Sonatinas, violin, piano, D. 408, G minor -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Tzigane, 1953 December 1; 1953 December 8; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 1)
      Information handwritten in pencil and blue ink on box:
      E3RC-3332-3333-3334-1Mas- Sonatina - Schubert
      E3RC-3072-3073-1Mas- Tzigane - Ravel
      15" Mas. dubbs.
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: December 1 and 8, 1953
    - Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 1, 1953 December 3; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 2)
      E3RC 3097-3099-3100-1Mas- Sonata - Bloch
      15” Dubb
      Recording date from original collection inventory: December 3, 1953
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Concertos, violin, string orchestra, BWV 1042, E major, 1953 December 6; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 3)
      Information handwritten in pencil and blue crayon on box:
      Bach (E) Concerto
      Bach E-Maj
      E3-RC-3329-1, 3330-1, 3331-1
      Mas. Tape 15”/sec
      Recording date from original collection inventory: December 6, 1953
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Concertos, violin, string orchestra, BWV 1041, A minor, 1953 December 6; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 4)
      Information handwritten in pencil and black crayon on box:
      Bach (A) Concerto
      Bach A Minor
      E3-RC-3326-1, 3327-1, 3328-1
      To Listen - Bach & Hungarian
      Master Tape 15”/sec
    - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Serenade, string orchestra, op. 48, C major. Valse -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Ungarische Tänze. Nr. 7, 1953 December 9; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 5)
      Information handwritten in black crayon on box:
      Tschaikowsky (Valse) / Brahms (Hung. Dance #7)
      Tchaikowsky Waltz E3-RC-2550-1
      Hungarian Dance #7 E3-RC-2551-1
      Recording date from original collection inventory: December 9, 1953
    - Sinding, Christian, 1856-1941. Suites, violin, piano, op. 10, A minor, 1953 December 9; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 6)
      E3RC-3010-3011-3012-1Mas
      Suite - Sinding
    - Franck, César, 1822-1890. Quintet, piano, strings, F minor, 1961 August 21; 1961 August 22; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 7)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; Leonard Pennario, piano; additional performers unidentified
      Franck: Piano Quintet with Pennario
      1st mov’t - M2-RB-3423 take 7 -- 2nd mov’t - M2-RB-3424 take 2 -- 3rd mov’t - M2-RB-3425 take 11
      15 inches per second MONO
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: August 21 and 22, 1961
    - Spohr, Louis, 1784-1859. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 8, op. 47, A minor -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Sérénade mélancolique, 1954 November 3; 1954 October 29; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 8)
      Spohr Concerto #8
      E4-RC-0547-1M [letter M is circled] 1st & 2nd Mvts. 10:25
      E4-RC-0548-1M [letter M is circled] 3rd Mvt. 7:06
      Tchakowski - Serenade Melancolique
      E4-RC-9000-1 M [letter M is circled] 6:25?
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: November 3, 1954 (Spohr) and October 29, 1954 (Tchaikovsky)
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 77, D major, 1955 February 21; 1955 February 22; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 9)
      Brahms Violin Concerto
      Heifetz - Reiner - Chicago Symphony
      MONAURAL
      15”/sec transfer from edited masters Ampex Tape
      F2-RH-1600-1 Pt. 1-First Mvt. Pt. 1 -- 1600-1 Pt. 2 - First Mvt. Concl. -- 1601-1 Second Mvt. -- 1602-1 Third Mvt.
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: February 21 and 22, 1955
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 77, D major, 1955 February 21; 1955 February 22; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 10)
      Monaural Transfer from Binaural Masters
      Corrected Masters
      15”/sec Ampex Tape
    - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Octet, violins (4), violas, violoncellos, op. 20, E♭ major, 1961 August 24; 1961 August 25; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 11)
      Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Gregor Piatigorsky, violoncello; additional performers unidentified
      Mendelssohn: Octet
      1st mov’t - M2-RB-3430 take 6 -- 2nd mov’t - M2-RB-3431 take 4 -- 3rd mov’t - M2-RB-3432 take 3 -- 4th mov’t - M2-RB-3433 take 12
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: August 24 and 25, 1961
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Sextets, violins, violas, violoncellos, no. 2, op. 36, G major, 1961 August 28; 1961 August 29; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 12)
      Brahms: Sextet
      1st mov’t - M2-RB-3426 take 6 -- 2nd mov’t - M2-RB-3427 take 10 -- 3rd mov’t - M2-RB-3428 take 2 -- 4th mov’t - M2-RB-3429 take 7
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: August 28 and 29, 1961
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, violins, violas, violoncello, K. 516, G minor, 1961 August 29; 1961 August 30; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 13)
      Mozart: Quintet, K. 516
      1st mov’t - M2-RB-3438 take 7 -- 2nd mov’t - M2-RB-3439 take 3 -- 3rd mov’t - M2-RB-3440 take 1 -- 4th mov’t - M2-RB-3441 take 12
      Information handwritten in red crayon on spine of box:
      (2 violas)
      Recording dates from original collection inventory: August 29 and 30, 1961
    - Heifetz Solo Album, Side One, 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 14)
      Composer and timing information handwritten in black ink on box
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (2:10; 3:30; 2:21) -- Bennett, Robert Russell, 1894-1981 (2:24; 3:04; 2:10) -- Shulman, Alan (1:12) -- Khachaturi︠a︡n, Aram Ilʹich, 1903-1978 (2:14) -- Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840 (2:53; 2:35)
      15"
    - Heifetz Solo Album, Side Two, 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 15)
      Sgambati, Giovanni, 1841-1914 (3:05) -- Kroll, William, 1901-1980 (2:33) -- Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 (2:04) -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 (2:18) -- Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975 (1:05) -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 (2:27) -- Dinicu, Grigoraș (2:09) -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 (9:15)
      15”
    - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 35, D major, 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 16)
      Jascha Heifetz 1520 Gilcrest Drive Beverly Hills
      15” Dubb - Korngold - Copy of O.K. Master
    - Miscellaneous Tape, 195-; 1 10 1/2" open reel tape (Box 26, Reel 17)
      Information written on box conflicts with information found inside box.